Okay, in this lecture, we're going to discuss about the next architecture consideration,
which is selecting the right embedding model, text embeddings represent vector representation
of unstructured text and images such as documents, sentences and so on.
So earlier we already discussed, let's say we have PDF document, we create chunks, pass
it through the embedding model and then it creates the output vector embeddings.
And you can see here we have 1536 dimensions and we have taken the Amazon Titan Analytics.
So now, how do we select the right embedding model?
So the first thing you need to consider is whether your input text is only text or
is it a combination of text, image and so on, because a lot of models only support text,
some other support text and images as well.
So let's take a look at couple of them.
So here you have Amazon Titan text embedding V2 model, which supports only text embeddings.
Then we have another model from Amazon Titan multimodal embeddings G1 and its input modalities
are text and image.
So first, you need to consider for your use case, what is the input modality?
The next is the output.
So there are various dimensions in which you can generate the output vector size.
It can be 256, 512, or 1024 and if you can see here for Amazon Titan text embeddings,
it comes in three variations, 512, 256, and 1024.
So for your use case, you also need to consider what is the max input text token size
or the text character size and based on that, you can select the embedding model.
So you can see for the Titan text embedding model, max input text token 8192 and max input
text characters is 50,000.
So how do you select the right embedding model for your use case?
So there's a trade-off between quality, cost, and latency.
So if you select a higher dimensional embedding and if you see here, we have 1024, 512,
and 256.
So if you select a higher one, maybe 1024, you have better recall, but there is going to
be higher cost.
And obviously if you select a lower dimensional embedding, it's going to be faster, cheaper,
but there's going to be lower accuracy.
Then you should also match the language and multilingual needs that you might have for
a use case.
So each embedding model supports different languages, so in this case, for Amazon Titan
text, you can see it supports English and 100 plus languages, but it's still in the preview
mode.
So you should review the multilingual needs for your use case.
And then you should also consider your inference type, whether you want an on-demand or
provision throughput.
So Amazon Titan text supports both scenarios.
So if I quickly show you through the console, so I'm on the bedrock knowledge base, you
can see the embedding model here.
So if I just click on the embedding model, so I can see two model providers with Amazon
and here there are three options, Amazon, no multimodal embeddings, Titan embeddings and Titan
text embeddings.
And then you just provide some details around these three models.
Then I can also select cohere, here I have embed English and embed multi-lingual.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.